You will pay...
（女）許さない…
You will pay!
許さない！
That demon...
あの悪魔…
I swear you will pay for this!
絶対に許さない
Come to me.
来て…
来て！　お願い！
Come to me! Please!
Is it you who dares to summon
me from such a lowly station?
（クロ）
身の程知らずにも
この私を呼び出したのは
あなたですか？
If you'll grant my wish,
I don't care if you're a demon!
（女）
願いを聞き届けてくれるのなら
悪魔でもかまわない！
You can have my soul! So, please...
私の魂をあげる
だから お願い！
あいつを！　あいつらを…
Make them...
クフッ いいでしょう
Very well.
暇潰しに その願いを
聞き届けてさしあげます
Granting your wish will give
me something to do, at least.
Thank you... And my payment...
（女）ありがとう　報酬は…
Indeed. Our contract is complete.
ふむ… 契約は成立です
Your emotions tasted sublime.
あなたの感情は とても美味でした
ですので これは大サービスですよ
For that reason, I will
do you a great service.
That said,
とはいえ この程度の報酬では
もって３日というところ
this payment will only
last three days, at most.
To make up for the rest... let's see...
足りない分は まあ…
I suppose I'll help myself to your prey.
あなたの獲物で賄うとしましょう
クフッ
クッフフフ… 久しぶりの現世です
Much time has passed since
I came to the living world.
I shall enjoy it to the fullest.
せいぜい楽しむとしましょうか
That Time I Got Reincarnated as a Slime
Episode 24: Black and the Mask
The Kingdom of Filtwood.
（ナレーション）
フィルトウッド王国
This nation borders the Great Forest of Jura,
ジュラの大森林に面する この国に
and Shizu paid a visit there,
after receiving an urgent request.
緊急の依頼を受けたシズが
訪れていた
The request was to defeat a
demon that had been revived.
依頼は 復活した悪魔の討伐である
Welcome to Filtwood Castle.
（騎士）
ようこそ フィルトウッド城へ
光栄です
It's a real honor
to meet the famous Conqueror of Flames!
かの有名な“爆炎の支配者”に
お会いできるとは
Right this way.
どうぞ こちらへ
（騎士）大広間まで ご案内します
I'll show you to the reception hall.
Shizue Izawa!
（冒険者たち）
シズエ･イザワ…
爆炎の支配者だ
The Conqueror of Flames!
Now, this is reassuring.
なんと心強い
Wow... They've gathered up quite a few.
（シズ）
へえ… また随分と集めたものね
Hey!
（クーガー）
よお！　シズさんじゃないか
If it isn't Shizu!
Good to see you again, Cougar-san.
（シズ）お久しぶり クーガーさん
You got the armor, too, huh?
あんたも この依頼を受けたのか
It was a request from the nation.
（シズ）国からの依頼だったからね
Man, you're as serious as ever!
（クーガー）
くう〜
あんたは相変わらず真面目だな
そんなもん適当な理由を作って
ブッチすりゃいいんだよ
You could've just come up with
some random reason to ditch it.
（シズ）
そう言う あなただって
ここにいるじゃない
Well, you're here, too, aren't you?
Hey, I'm just here for the pay.
（クーガー）
まあよ 俺としては報酬にな
But...
だが 今となっちゃあ後悔してるぜ
I sorta regret it now.
Apparently, at least ten really skilled
adventurers have died already.
（小声で）
既に 10人以上の腕利きが
やられちまってるらしい
I see.
（シズ）なるほどね
But the arrival of the champion
is gonna give hope to everyone!
英雄の登場とくれば
希望が湧いてくるってもんさ
You're exaggerating.
（シズ）大げさだよ
（槍(やり)で床をたたく音）
（クーガー）お？
That's the minister.
（クーガー）大臣だ
（大臣）
冒険者諸君 残念な知らせじゃ
Adventurers, I bring unfortunate news.
Our champions, the two
Silver Wings, have passed on.
我らが英雄“銀嶺(ぎんれい)の翼”のお二方が
亡くなられた
What?!
（冒険者たち）
なんだって！
あの２人が？
Those two?!
Are you serious?
マジかよ…
It appears their bodies were
devoured with no trace left behind.
（大臣）
遺体は
跡形もなく食い尽くされたようじゃ
The request given to you is to
defeat the resurrected demon.
今回の依頼は
復活した悪魔の討伐である
This account has been found
in a century-old text.
100年前の文献にも記述があった
The champion Orthos, huh?
（クーガー）英雄オルトスか
But all this tells us
（大臣）
しかし これには
国家騎士オルトスによって
is that the demon was successfully
sealed away by the knight Orthos.
封印に成功したとしか
記されておらぬ
It does not mention how he sealed him.
どう封印したかは書かれてはいない
This is why we wish to rely
on all of your strengths.
だから ぜひとも 皆様のお力に
すがらせてほしいのです
There's not enough info on the enemy!
（冒険者たち）
敵の情報が足りてない！
死ねと言っているのか
Are you telling us to go die?!
The Silver Wings were heroes
famous enough to have titles!
銀嶺っていえば
二つ名持ちの英雄だぞ
If they failed, there aren't enough
lives between all of us to survive this!
その２人が失敗したヤマなんか
命がいくつあっても足りねえぞ！
I agree.
（シズ）
同感ね
Sorry, but this one's too dangerous. I'm out.
悪いが こんな危険な依頼
俺は降りるぜ
Wait!
お待ちを
悪魔を倒すためには
We need the help of all of
you to defeat this demon!
どうしても
あなた方の協力が必要なのです
Shut up!
うるせえ！　あ…
Oh, man...
Please, calm down!
（大臣）どうか落ち着いてくだされ
実は 悪魔が何を狙っておるのか
In truth, the one thing we do
know is what the demon is after.
それだけは判明しておるのです
What do you mean?
どういうことだ？
城の地下の大広間に
遺体が安置されているのです
There are remains laid to rest in the
castle's underground reception hall.
Those remains are the
very body of that demon,
それこそが悪魔の肉体であり
それを取り戻して
完全復活することが
and his objective is to recover
it and complete his resurrection.
悪魔の目的なのです
The demon's...
悪魔の…
遺体？
...remains?
Ah! That must be the renowned Shizue Izawa!
おお！
高名なシズエ･イザワ殿ですな
I will gladly answer any question you ask.
何なりと お答えしますとも
If this demon drove the
kingdom to the brink of ruin
（シズ）
国家を滅亡の危機にまで陥れ
and defeated the two Silver Wings,
銀嶺の翼の２人を倒したとなると
he may be a superior demon, an Archdemon.
上位悪魔 アークデーモンに
匹敵する可能性も
Yes...
That brings me to my question.
（シズ）そこで疑問なのですが…
Does this demon have a name?
（シズ）
その悪魔に呼び名はあるのですか？
Monsters gain far greater power
when they are granted names.
（ナレーション）
魔物は
名前を得ることで力が大幅に増す
This was common knowledge
among all capable adventurers.
これは 実力のある冒険者の間では
常識だった
No, there are no accounts indicating
that the demon had a name.
いいえ 悪魔が名乗ったという
記述はございません
If he has no name, he can't be an Archdemon.
（シズ）
名前がないなら
アークデーモンには至ってないか
But it's hard to imagine the
Silver Wings losing otherwise.
でも そうなると
銀嶺が負けるとは考えにくい
So your intent was to bring us all
here to wait for the demon to arrive?
（シズ）
それで 私たちを この場にとどめて
悪魔が来るのを
待つおつもりなのですね？
Indeed.
（大臣）さよう
Now that the Silver Wings have fallen,
銀嶺が敗れた今となっては
この策にかけるしかないのです
this strategy is our only hope.
（シズ）
と… 言う割には
私たちを敵だと思っているみたい
He says that, but he seems
to see us as enemies.
Screw that! I have no obligation
to serve this nation!
ふざけるな！
俺は
この国に従う義務なんぞないんだ
I'm outta here!
帰らせてもらうぞ
He killed him!
斬りやがった！
What's the meaning of this?!
（冒険者たち）
どういうつもりだ！
おい 何を考えて…
Hey! What are you thinking?!
（騎士隊長）黙れ！
Quiet! Before you curse me,
take a good look at this man!
罵る前に この男をよく…
見るがいい！
What is this?!
（冒険者）何だ こいつは？
What's going on?
（クーガー）なんてこった…
A lesser demon...
（シズ）
レッサーデーモン？
見たか！
貴様たちを この場に隔離したのは
You see that? We have isolated
all of you in this location
because some of you may have been
possessed by demons, like he was.
こいつのように悪魔に憑(つ)かれた者が
いるやもしれぬからだ
It would behoove you all to
do as we say and cooperate.
貴様たちは我らに従い
協力するように
変なマネをすれば
Try anything funny, and you can expect
to be seen as a demon and cut down.
悪魔と見なして
斬り捨てられると覚悟せよ
This has turned ugly.
（シズ）
面倒なことになった
マズいな こりゃ…
パニックになりかけてやがる
This looks bad. These guys are panicking.
Makes sense, if it's possible
someone could be possessed.
体を乗っ取られてる可能性が
あるとはな
That would include you and me, Shizu.
シズさんも俺も例外じゃねえ
True.
（シズ）そうね
So he wants us to find out ourselves
which among us are the demons?
（シズ）
私たちを互いに探り合わせて
あぶり出すつもり？
（クロ）クッフフフ
（シズ）あ…
Who's this guy?
（冒険者たち）
何だ こいつ？
見ない顔だな
No idea. Never seen him before.
（クロ）クッハハハ…
Shizu...
シズさん…
（シズ）ええ かなりの実力者ね
Yes. He's very powerful.
He seems to be a mage,
but he shows no weaknesses.
魔法使いのようだけど 隙がないわ
Unbelievable... I didn't even
sense his presence before.
（シズ）
信じられない
今の今まで全く気配を感じなかった
（クロ）クフッ
ここに悪魔がいる…
そう思わせることで
By making us believe there was a demon here,
you hoped to build cooperation
among all of us, didn't you?
互いに協力関係を
築けないようにしたわけですね
What are you saying?
（大臣）貴様… 何が言いたい？
（クロ）クッフフ
Oh, it just seemed that this request would
be completed far more easily than expected.
いえね 思ったよりも簡単に
依頼が達成できそうだったもので
I couldn't help but laugh.
つい笑ってしまいました
Captain of the knights...
（クロ）騎士隊長様
（騎士隊長）あっ…
You said that if we tried anything funny,
we'd be seen as demons and cut down, right?
（クロ）
先ほど“変なマネをすれば
悪魔と見なして斬り捨てる”
とおっしゃいましたね
So, what will it be?
さて どうします？
私は あなた方に
従うつもりはありませんし
I have no intention of obeying you people,
nor do I have any intention of
playing along with this charade.
自作自演に
つきあうつもりもないのです
Charade, you say?
（騎士隊長）自作自演だと？
Yes.
It was you who summoned the lesser demon.
レッサーデーモンを召喚したのは
あなた方でしょ？
Are you trying to mock me?!
貴様… 我らを愚弄するつもりか！
You may intend to gloss over it,
勢いでごまかすつもりでしょうが
お粗末と言わざるをえませんね
but I must say, your efforts are pathetic.
You dare defy the principles of this nation?!
国家の方針に逆らうつもりか！
Oh, no. It saves me a great deal
of work, so I'm all for it.
（クロ）
いいえ 面倒な手間が省けるので
大賛成ですよ
Huh?
The request was to defeat a revived demon,
復活した悪魔の討伐
という依頼ですが
but there is no restriction saying the
demon is the only one we can kill.
なにも悪魔だけしか殺してはならぬ
という制限などありません
This nation's principle
seems to be much the same.
この国の方針も同じみたいですし
I've simply determined that there's no
reason I should be the only one rebuked.
私だけが とがめられるいわれも
ないと判断しました
それは どういう…
What do you...
Do you intend to slaughter
everyone here to find the demon?
（シズ）あなた…
（クーガー）え？
（シズ）
この場にいる者を皆殺しにして
悪魔を探し出すつもり？
Correct.
（クロ）正解です
I am Shizu.
（シズ）私はシズ
Who... are you?
あなた… 何者なの？
You can call me... Kuro.
（クロ）
クロ… とでも お呼びください
It was an imitation name given
to me by an old acquaintance.
古き知り合いからの呼称の
もじりです
Kuro...
（シズ）
クロ…
あなたの行動は許容できないわ
I cannot tolerate what you're doing.
In that case, you shall
be the first one I kill.
それでは
あなたから始末するとしましょう
（シズ）私には炎は効かないわよ
Flames have no effect on me.
I see... A superior spirit...
なるほど 上位精霊ですか
And it even identifies with you.
しかも 同一化とは…
That will be a slight hassle,
but no real problem.
少々やっかいですが
問題ないレベルです
I shall play with you for a bit.
少しだけ
遊びに つきあってさしあげますよ
Don't underestimate me.
（シズ）ナメないで
クフッ
W-Wow...
ス… スゲえ
That's the power of the champion
who reigns at the top?
これが頂点に君臨する英雄の力か
シズさん…
Shizu...
Just who are you?
（シズ）あなたは 一体…
Should one who is about to
die be concerned with that?
死にゆく者が
それを気にしますか？
Knowing will only bring you despair...
知っても きっと
絶望するだけですよ
If you knew at all, that is!
知っていたらの話ですがね！
Of course, who I am is no business of yours.
（クロ）もっとも 私が誰であれ
あなたには関係のないことでしょう
True, it isn't.
（シズ）確かに関係ない
But letting you run free
would be far too dangerous.
だけど あなたを野放しにするのは
あまりに危険よ
So I'm sorry, but I'm about to get serious!
悪いけど
本気を出させてもらうわね！
（クロ）クフフフ… 面白い
Interesting.
That lax attitude will be what kills you.
（シズ）
その余裕が あなたの命取りよ
I'm ending this now!
これで終わらせる
インフェルノフレイム！
Inferno Flame!
（クーガー）マジかよ！
Seriously?!
（クロ）クッフフフフ…
Excellent.
見事です
How remarkable that a mere human is capable
of using Ifrit's power at this level.
たかが人間が イフリートの力を
ここまで行使するとは
It has been some time since I truly
felt that I was fighting, as I do now.
久々に
戦っているという気がしますよ
So you're a demon... It's hard to believe.
（シズ）まさか デーモンとはね
He's unharmed after taking
those flames head-on?
あの爆炎をくらって無傷かよ
No, I must correct you.
（クロ）いいえ 訂正を１つ
I am not unharmed. I did feel a bit of pain.
無傷ではなく
多少の痛みは感じました
That is exactly what makes this fight so fun.
だからこそ 戦いは面白い
さて… それでは
そろそろ終わらせましょう
Now, let's put an end to this.
（クロ）なに！
What?!
Impossible... That mask...
バカな… その仮面 その時間厚は
That time compression... Is it... infinity?
まさか… 無限？
Infinity?!
無限だと！
I can only assume that
your mask surpasses time.
その仮面… 時を超えているとしか
思えませんね
To think there's a human
who can use such an item...
そんな代物を扱う人間がいるとは
クフフフ… とても興味深い！
How intriguing!
いいでしょう
今回は ここまでにいたしましょう
Very well. That will be enough for today.
Awesome!
（冒険者たち）
スゲえ！
さすが爆炎の支配者！
That's our Conqueror of Flames!
やったぜ！
Way to go!
我らとしても 冒険者の方々を
We have no intention whatsoever
of neglecting you adventurers.
ないがしろにするつもりなど
毛頭ない
We only need to know the demon's identity.
悪魔の正体が分かれば
それでよいのです
Thank goodness he withdrew.
（シズ）
向こうが引いてくれて助かった
His strength... He was
holding back against me.
あの強さ…
私を相手に余力を残していた
それに…
And...
（クロ）クッフフ
Oh, it just seemed that my request would
be completed far more easily than expected.
いえね 思ったよりも簡単に
依頼が達成できそうだったもので
Request? Who could employ
such a powerful demon?
（シズ）
依頼？　あれほどの悪魔を
使役する者がいるなんて…
Unbelievable.
信じられない
Demon Lord Leon told me once
（シズ）
魔王レオンに聞いたことがある
of demons who were known as the progenitors.
原初と呼ばれる悪魔がいたことを
These demons are quite heretical,
making them rather troublesome.
（レオン）
その悪魔は特に異端で
とても やっかいなのだ
In place of names, each of them is
referred to by their signature color.
（レオン）
彼らは名前の代わりに
それぞれの特徴の色で呼ばれている
The Red Progenitor, Rouge...
原初の赤 ルージュ
原初の白 ブラン
The White Progenitor, Blanc...
そして 原初の黒 ノワール
And the Black Progenitor, Noir.
Black... Noir...
（シズ）
黒(クロ)… ノワール…
まさかね
It couldn't be.
Such a being wouldn't come here.
そんな大物が こんな所に…
Come in.
（シズ）どうぞ
Pardon the intrusion.
His Majesty wishes to speak with you.
失礼します
国王陛下が お話があるとのことで
Would you accompany me?
ご同行を願えないでしょうか
（シズ）分かったわ
All right.
You were brilliant in that fight earlier.
（騎士）
先ほどの戦い 実に見事でした
That demon was so frightened
of you that he—
あの悪魔も シズ殿を恐れて…
I was lucky to survive.
（シズ）生き残れたのは幸運でした
That demon was stronger than me.
あの悪魔は 私より強かったですよ
Please, there's no need to be modest.
（騎士）またまた ご謙遜を
逃がしてしまったのは
痛恨の極みですが
It is regrettable that he managed to escape,
but with you here, we have nothing to fear!
シズ殿がいれば
恐るるに足りませんよ！
Underground? Is this where
the demon's remains are?
（シズ）
地下？
悪魔の死体があるという所か
This knight...
あの騎士…
大広間では見かけなかった
I didn't see him in the reception hall.
So how did he know about
my fight with the demon?
なのに どうして
悪魔との戦いを知ってたの？
The minister and...
（シズ）
大臣と…
国王？
the king?
Thank you for coming, Shizu.
（騎士）よくぞ参ったな シズ殿
この国のために
その身を ささげてくださること
As king, I am grateful that you have
offered your life for this nation.
王として感謝するぞ
What's the meaning of this?
（シズ）どういうこと？
You are rather slow to catch on, aren't you?
（大臣）察しが悪いですなあ
You must be exhausted
after your battle earlier.
今のあなたは
先の戦いで疲労困憊(ひろうこんぱい)であろう
This is why we need to sacrifice
you while we still can.
じゃから 今のうちに
生贄(いけにえ)になってもらいたいのじゃ
I see... You were in
collusion from the start.
そう… 最初からグルだったのね
そのとおりさ
Precisely. My name is Orthos.
俺の名はオルトス
The Imperial Knight hailed
as a champion, Orthos...
英雄とされる国家騎士オルトス
So that's it.
そうだったの…
最初から封印されてなどいなかった
You were never sealed away at all.
You were a demon, an enemy of mankind.
人類の敵対者…
魔族だったわけね
I am the ruler of this land, as well.
（オルトス）
そして この地を統べる支配者さ
You meant to gather all the best
adventurers, eliminate them,
（シズ）
名だたる冒険者を呼び寄せ 始末し
and pass them off as demons...
魔族へと ささげる
Then you, the true demon,
would gain even more power.
そうして 悪魔は更なる力を得る
The Kingdom of Filtwood is ruled by demons,
このフィルトウッド王国は
魔族に支配された国であり
and the king is merely their puppet.
国王は魔族の傀儡(かいらい)となっていたのね
I watched through the minister's eyes.
大臣の目を通して見せてもらったよ
That demon was powerful,
but he disappointed me, in the end.
あの悪魔は なかなかだったが
最後は あっけないもんだ
それよりも 君のその仮面さ
What intrigues me more is your mask.
It seems to have significant value.
かなりの価値があるようだな
That makes it suitable for me to own.
それでこそ 俺が持つにふさわしい
I will suck out your blood,
devour your flesh,
君の血をすすり 肉を食らう
and make your power my own.
そして その力もまた
俺の物になるのさ
Aren't you glad?
うれしいだろ？
Be serious.
（シズ）ふざけるな
ハハハハ！　バカめ
Don't be a fool! Your magic
hasn't even recovered.
魔力も回復していない
そんな状態で
And you think you can defeat me?
この俺に勝てるとでも
思っているのか？
I have to face him without
any chance to prepare...
（シズ）
準備もなしに
相手にしないといけないなんて…
でも… やるしかない！
But I have no choice!
Ah, you still have that much strength left?
ほう？　まだ そんな力が
If you could injure me, you must
be stronger than the Silver Wings.
俺を傷つけるとは
銀嶺の２人より強いのだな
So it was you!
（シズ）やはり… あなたが
Indeed, though a lapse in my
attention allowed them to escape.
もっとも
油断して逃亡を許してしまったがね
But you will not get away.
だが 君は逃がさないよ
Did you know that there
are ranks among demons?
知ってるな？
悪魔にも階級があることを
I am of the legendary class,
a Greater Demon General...
この俺こそが
伝説級の存在である上位魔将
that is, an Archdemon!
アークデーモンなのさ！
Understand now? As a man-made hero,
（オルトス）分かるか？
人為的に英雄となった俺には
この国の民の声が力となる
the voices of this nation's
people give me power.
That power gave me a name,
その力が俺に名を与え
自らの力でネームドへと至ったのだ
allowing me to become a
named being on my own.
頂点たる あのお方のようにな
Just like that supreme being
who reigns at the top...
The top?
（シズ）頂点？
（オルトス）
フフフ…
お前ごときが知る必要のないことだ
There is no need for you to know.
Even one hailed as a champion
has no more power than this?!
英雄と呼ばれる者でさえ
この程度の力しかないとはな！
What's the matter?
Not going to unify with Ifrit?
どうした？
イフリートと同一化しないのか？
That would make you a little stronger.
そうすれば
少しはマシになるだろうに
I'm out of magic,
but Ifrit still has strength.
（シズ）
魔力は尽きたけど
イフリートの力は まだ残ってる
If I let it rampage, it should be
enough to defeat even an Archdemon!
これを暴走させれば
アークデーモンだろうと
滅ぼせるはず！
Now, we can't have that.
（クロ）困りますね
（シズ）ハッ…
How can one who caused me pain die
at the hands of this weakling?
（クロ）
私に痛みを与えた あなたが
この程度の雑魚に殺されるなんて
あ… あなた
You're...
It is my policy to keep my promises.
（クロ）
私は 必ず約束を守る主義なのです
クフッ
Wh-What is...
（国王）こ… これは！
Impossible! Our knights are renowned
for their unrivaled strength!
バカな！
無類の強さを誇る我が騎士たちが…
You call it "unrivaled strength" just
because they can kill a mere lesser demon?
たかがレッサーデーモンを
寄生させただけで
無類の強さだと？
あなた方の強さの基準は
低レベルすぎて話になりませんね
Your standards for strength are far too low.
うっ… 貴様は確かに強いが
You are indeed strong,
but you are no match for us!
それでも 我らの敵ではない
爆炎の支配者の次は お前だ
After the Conqueror of
Flames, you'll be next!
Just wait there—
そこで おとなしく… うっ！
あ… ひっ ひいい〜！
I-It can't be! We have the
protection of a greater demon!
そっ そんな…
グレーターデーモンによって
守護されているのに
ひいい…
Stop squealing, trash.
（クロ）さえずるなよ ゴミが
I never really thought he'd just escaped,
（シズ）
逃げ出したとは…
思っていなかったけど
but I had no idea he was hunting
down demons disguised as humans...
まさか 人に化けた悪魔たちを
狩ってたなんて
Just because you defeated our puppet,
我が操り人形を倒せたとて
do you think you can defeat
me, an Archdemon?
アークデーモンである俺に
勝てるとでも？
A lower demon like you can't—
貴様ごとき低俗な悪魔など…
Who are you calling "lower"?
誰が低俗だと？
For a dependent of Red,
you are overconfident.
赤の係累(けいるい)は自信過剰すぎる
That's why you can't judge how
powerful your opponents are.
だから
相手の力量も見定められないのだ
I-Impossible!
（オルトス）バッ バカな…
You... You are...
お前は… いや あなた様は…
You have disgraced yourself
by aligning with these demons.
（クロ）
お前のような
魔族に与(くみ)する恥さらしに
You don't deserve to live.
生きる資格などありません
魂までも破壊して
I will destroy your very soul
so that you can never be revived!
二度と復活できないように
してあげましょう
No... No!
（オルトス）いや… やめろ〜！
（クロ）クフッ
All the demons dwelling in the
Kingdom of Filtwood were purged.
（ナレーション）
フィルトウッド王国に巣くう
悪魔たちは
一掃された
The deaths of the king and minister were
proclaimed the work of the demon named Black,
国王や大臣の死は全て
クロという悪魔の
仕業とされ
and the records indicated
that Shizu defeated Black.
クロは
シズによって倒されたと
記録には残っている
Well, if we can keep our stories straight,
そう 口裏を合わせてくれれば
あなたを狙うのは
やめてさしあげますよ
I will refrain from targeting you.
Who the heck was that "Black" guy, anyway?
（クーガー）
結局 あのクロって野郎は
何者(なにもん)だったんだ？
（シズ）
知らないほうがいいと
思うよ
I think we're better off not knowing.
I guess. Sometimes ignorance
is bliss in this world.
（クーガー）そうだなあ
確かに世の中にゃあ
知らねえほうが
幸せなこともあらあなあ
Well, I'm heading out. Take care of yourself.
（クーガー）
それじゃあ
俺は行くけど
シズさんも元気でな
I will. Until we meet again.
（シズ）
ええ　またどこかで
Well, then...
さてと
I'm sure someone will do something
about that demon someday.
（シズ）
あの悪魔は…
いつか誰かが
なんとかしてくれるよね
And so, time passed...
（ナレーション）
そして 時は流れ…
クッフフフ
あの仮面が割れるとは…
That mask showed up again... So it's true.
やはり そうでしたか
That slime is...
あのスライムが…
あのお方こそが…
That being truly is...
クッフフフ
Thus, silent and one-sided though it was,
（ナレーション）
こうして ひそかに
そして 一方的に
Rimuru and Black had their
fateful first encounter.
リムルとクロは
運命の出会いを
果たしたのだった
〜♪
Black would later be summoned by Rimuru
and receive a name:
"Diablo."
〝ディアブロ〞と
Next time, "Tales: Veldora's Journal."
（大賢者(だいけんじゃ)）
次回「閑話:ヴェルドラ日記」
Tales: Veldora's Journal